<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ali&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ali&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:26:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://alihacks.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The one characater performance fix</title>
      <link>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2021-01-30-the-one-character-performance-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:26:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2021-01-30-the-one-character-performance-fix/</guid>
      <description>Note: This writeup is based on a production issue that I encountered for a vendor app. I used what I learned from the experience to write up an independent demo to show the potential impact this problem can have on a production system.
We&amp;rsquo;re going to demonstrate the impact of parameter data types on performance. For this scenario we will create a 1 table database that contains user sessions. During typical use, we&amp;rsquo;d have 1 row per active session in this table and inactive sessions are cleared on a schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting frequent occurrences of error 17830 in system_health</title>
      <link>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2020-11-29-troubleshooting-frequent-occurrences-of-error-17830-in-system_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:26:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2020-11-29-troubleshooting-frequent-occurrences-of-error-17830-in-system_health/</guid>
      <description>While analyzing the system_health on a few SQL Servers, I noticed that error 17830 is logged about 30 times every minute, and this behavior is consistent across a set of servers. After doing some googling, I came across a very detailed writeup about this error on bobsql.com. This post saved me quite a bit of troubleshooting time as it explained the details behind what may cause this error and a potential fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a custom Extended Event Session to get faster results from sp_blitzLock</title>
      <link>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2020-11-22-using-a-custom-extended-event-session-to-get-faster-results-from-sp_blitzlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:26:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alihacks.github.io/posts/2020-11-22-using-a-custom-extended-event-session-to-get-faster-results-from-sp_blitzlock/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty new to sp_blitzLock which is a great utility stored procedure that&amp;rsquo;s part of the First Responder Kit that makes analyzing deadlocks simpler by parsing out a lot of the information from the XML deadlock reports. Unfortunately, I have noticed that on some servers, runtime of the SP can take quite a while. My analysis has shown that this is not really an issue with sp_blitzLock but rather SQL Server&amp;rsquo;s ability to work with XML.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
